Guide to the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions (SEHNAP) Collection of Dissertations and Theses RG.26.35
New York University Archives
School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions (SEHNAP) of Dissertations and Theses
1940-1995
New York University Archives
New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions
RG.26.35
15 Linear Feet in 15 record cartons
The School of Education Collection of Dissertations and Theses dates from 1940 to 1995 and contains student dissertations and theses from four academic departments within the school. The thesis topics vary widely in subject and time period.
Arrangement
The files remain in their original order and are grouped into two series based on the academic department of the thesis or dissertation.
Scope and Contents
The School of Education Collection of Dissertations and Theses dates from 1950 to 1995 and contains dissertations and theses on a broad range of topics pertaining to art history, education, nursing, and health across diverse geographical and historical categories. Many of the theses and dissertations are bound, and some are in multiple volumes.
Historical Note
The School of Pedagogy at New York University was founded in 1890 and renamed the School of Education in 1921. From 1974 to 1994, the school was known as the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions (SEHNAP) from 1974 to 1994. In 2007, the school was renamed the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for use without restrictions.
Custodial History
The Art and Arts Professions dissertations were transferred to the New York University Archives by the Department of Art and Arts Professions in 1997. Details on regarding the transfer of materials in Series II and III are not available.
Romanticism -- England; Theses.; Paris (France) -- History.; Dissertations.; Art -- Study and teaching.; Industrial design.; Artists -- Thailand; Art -- Nigeria.; Jaina art.; Jones Beach State Park (N.Y.); Failaka Island (Kuwait); Child development -- 20th century; Mental health.; Nursing. -- 20th century; Acconci, Vito, 1940-; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929; Hesse, Eva, 1936-1970; New York University. Department of Art and Art Professions; Demuth, Charles, 1883-1935; Greenberg, Clement, 1909-1994; Anderson, Walter Inglis, 1903-1965; Bochner, Mel, 1940-; K.K. Kunsthistorisches Hofmuseum (Vienna, Austria)
- Series I: Department of Art and Art Professions Dissertations, 1940-1995; 9 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons
  Historical Note
  The Department of Art and Art Professions is part of the New York University School of Education, which is currently called the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development. At the beginning of the period represented by this series, the School of Education's Art courses were taught within Art Education, a program that focused on the training of teachers, supervisors, and directors of art education in elementary and secondary schools. By the 1990s, the renamed Department of Art and Art Professions had expanded to offer majors in Studio Art, Arts Education, Art Therapy, and Arts Administration, offering a PhD in Arts and Humanities or Art Education. In the 1940s, PhD candidates in the department of Art Education spent at least one year working on what was then referred to as a thesis. By the 1990s, students in Art and Arts Professions produced dissertations as part of their PhD requirements.
  - Untitled Dissertation on Thai Art, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227125 7
  - A Study of the Works of Twelve Modern Thai Painters, Jamuni, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Modern Thai Painting: A Study of Twelve Thai Painters in the Context of Thai Tradition and Changing Art Education, Jamuni, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Tripartite Description of Jaina-Style Figurines, Kellers. Vol. 2 - Illustrations, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Tripartite Description of Jaina-Style Figurines, Kellers. Vol. 3 - Computer Printouts, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Tripartite Description of Jaina-Style Figurines, Kellers. Vol. 1 - Text and Bibliography, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Influence of Romanticism on British Painting of the Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries, Smith, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A Hermeneutic Study of Selected Paintings of Women Religious Artists of the 12th and 20th Centuries, by Therese McGuire. Vol. 1, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227126 5
  - From Socrates to Thomas, by R.F. Shubart. Vol. 1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - An Analysis of the Concept of the Artist's Intention in the Visual Arts, by Gertrude Kessel, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Guidelines for a Course on Women Artists, Arnold, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clement Greenberg: His Critical and Personal Relationships with Jackson Pollock and Selected Post Painterly Abstractionists, by Janet Jones, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Papermaking from Selected Malaysian Fibers: An Investigation of its Artistic Potential Through Creation of Paper Artworks, by Chew Teng Beng, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Malcah Zeldis: Her Life and Evolution of her Work, by Henry Niemann, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227127 3
  - The Art of Windsor Chairmaker: An Aesthetic Inquiry, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - An Abstract of Ways of Meaning in Selected Contemporary Sculpture Manifesting Hard and Soft Form Characteristics, by Carl Rattner, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - An Abstract Toward the Development of a Critically Responsive Audience: An Aesthetic Inquiry Employing Edward Bullough's Theory and Criticism of Contemporary Theatre, by Nina M. Wasserman, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Design Dilemma: A Study of the New Morality of Industrial Design in Western Societies, by Marcia M.O. Sampaio Rosefelt, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Design Dilemma: A Study of the New Morality of Industrial Design in Western Societies, by Marcia M.O. Sampaio Rosefelt, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Development of a Model for the Operation of a University Art Gallery, by Gene Ellis Sills, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227128 1
  - Integrating the Arts in Public Education: The Symbolization Process as Wholistic Experience, by Jerrilee Cain, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - A Phenomenological Approach to Aesthetic Education in the Secondary School Painting Class, by Barry Paul Lieberman, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Symbolic Meaning of the Cross in Contemporary American Painting. A Comparative Study of Statements by Selected Artists and Critics, by Walter Gaudnek, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - An Abstract of The Art of Eva Hesse, Mel Bochner, and Vito Acconci as Indicative of Shifts in Mainstream Art Between 1966 and 1973, by Martha Smith-Allen, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for the Re-Certification of the New York University Art Education Programs, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - A Study of the Development of An Artist: Charles Demuth, by A. Eisman, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227129 9
  - Paris: The City of Light, by Dale McConathy, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Paris: The Culture Industry - A Guide, by Dale McConathy, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Paris: Between the Wars by by Dale McConathy, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sacred Space: An Aesthetic for the Liturgical Environment, by Dennis McNally, SJ, 19682 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Five Plays: A Repetory of Children's Theatre to be Performed by and for Children, by Lowell S. Swortzell, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sacred Space: An Aesthetic for the Liturgical Environment, by Dennis McNally, SJ, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell - Projected Color Images as Stimuli for Gravure I, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell - Projected Color Images as Stimuli for Gravure II, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hug - The Origin and Development of the Teacher Education Unit at New York University, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Randall - The Progress of Transformation in Contemporary Assemblage copy 2, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Ceramics of Failaka: A Question of the Function of Tradition in Artistic Creation, by Safwat Nourel-Din, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Role of the Visual Arts in Post-Modern and Late-Modern Architecture: A Comparative Study. Final Dissertation Copy. Robert J. Daniel, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227130 7
  - Integrated Art Education, by M. Colleen Harrigan, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Development of Case Studies and Conceptual Analyses of Effects of Art Therapy with Emotionally Disturbed and Brain-Injured Adolescents, by Erika Steinberger, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Puerto Rican Art in New York: Painters and Their Work, by Patricia Wilson, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Kunsthistorisches Museum in Vienna, by Evelyn Samuel, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Relationship Between the Crafts and the Fine Arts in the United States from 1876 to 1980, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Validity in Biblical Interpretation, by F. Eugene Guest, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - A Creative Process Produces an Autobiographical Novel: An Aesthetic Historical Study, by Carl A. Winderl, jr. vol. I, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227131 5
  - A Creative Process Produces an Autobiographical Novel: An Aesthetic Historical Study, by Carl A. Winderl, jr. vol. II, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A Creative Process Produces an Autobiographical Novel: An Aesthetic Historical Study, by Carl A. Winderl, jr. vol. III, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - A Creative Process Produces an Autobiographical Novel: An Aesthetic Historical Study, by Carl A. Winderl, jr. vol. IV, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - A Study of the Origins, Development, and Significance of Southern Nigerian Traditional Pottery, Moses Oladipo Fowowe, vol. I, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - A Study of the Origins, Development, and Significance of Southern Nigerian Traditional Pottery, Moses Oladipo Fowowe, vol. II, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Dissertation (Embroidery in Jordan) by Insaf Frain, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ornstein: A Guide to Creative Art and Science Experiences in the Third and Fourth Grades of the Elementary School II, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227132 3
  - Ornstein: Intesifying Learning Through Creative Experiences in Art and Science in the Third and Fourth Grades of the Elementary School I, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Arts and Crafts as Factors in Social Adjustment With Special Reference to Juvenile Deliquency, Benjamin Katz, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Introduction to the Study of Contemporary Civilization: A Textbook and Study Guide, Katharine Augusta Sutton, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sparrow: The Choreographic Devices: Their Nature and Function as Related to the Principle of Opposition, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation The Environmental Design of Jones Beach State Park: Aesthetic and Ecological Aspects of the Park's Architecture and Landscape, by R. Marc Fasanelle, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Natural Forms: The Horn Island Logs and Watercolors of Walter Inglis Anderson (1903-1965), Cynthia Elyce Rubin, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Kolodny - An Interpretative Study of the Social, Political, Economic and Educational Views of Thorstein Veblen, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227133 1
  - Boyum - The Grapes the Lilac Grows, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Gall - Creative Work for Children Talented in Art, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Crawford - Counseling with Teachers Concerning Visual Education, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Tobin - Art Experiences for the Maladjusted Adolescent, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell - Projected Color Images as Stimuli for Gravure IV, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell - Projected Color Images as Stimuli for Gravure III, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series II: Education, Health, and Nursing Theses, 1950-1989; 6 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons
  - An Investigation of the Relationship of Self-Disclosure, Interpersonal Dependency, and Life Changes to Loneliness in Young Adults by Noreen Elizabeth Mahon, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Comparison between Meditating Subjects and Non-Meditating Subjects on Time Experience and Human Field Motion by Janet Macrae [envelope], 1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Comparison between Meditating Subjects and Non-Meditating Subjects on Time Experience and Human Field Motion by Janet Macrae [envelope], 1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Body-Cathexis, Personal Values and Attitudes Toward the Disabled, In First Year Baccalaureate Nursing Students by Helen Isabel MacRae, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - An Investigation of Nurses' Empathy and Critical Thinking Ability to Accuracy of Perception of Patients' Acute Pain Experiences by Linda F. Maciorowski, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sharing of Common Fears Between Mothers and Four and Five Year Old Children in Middle-Class Families by Colleen Lynch [envelope] [quantity:2], 1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Energy Wave Pattern Manifest in Red and Blue Light and Human Field Motion in Those With Visual Perception and With Blindness by Betty Ludomirski-Kalmanson, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - The Relation of Ethnicity and Ego Defensiveness of Female Registered Nurses to Their Attitudes Toward Ethnically Similar and Different Patients by Kem Betty Louie, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship Between the Environmental Energy Wave Frequency Pattern Manifest in Red Light and Blue Light and Human Field Motion in Adult Individuals With Visual Sensory Perception and Those With Total Blindness by Betty G. Ludomirski, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Sharing of Common Fears Between Mothers and Their Eleven Year-Old Children in Middle-Class Families by Suzanne Lego [envelope] [quantity:2], 1971 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Perceived Body Space and Self-Esteem in Adult Males With and Without Chronic Low Back Pain by Phyllis Lisanti [envelope], 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Relationship Between Alcohol Consumption, Satisfaction and Experienced Control Among Women by Carolyn R. Lansberry, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Separation Anxiety, Conceptual Perspective Taking, and Social Competency in Nursery School Children in a Novel Situation by Arlene S. Kreinik, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Psychoprophylaxis in Childbirth and Changes in Self-Concept of the Participant Husband and His Concept of His Wife byJacqueline Hott, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Variations in Speech, Blocking Agents in Speech, Decision Time, and Conflict in Marital Dyads by Patricia Hurley [envelope], 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Risk Taking Characteristics, Belief in Internal-External Control, Emotional Reactivity, and the Lethality of the Suicide Plan in Women Who Have Attempted Suicide by Hanna M. Jacobson, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - How Can The Technique of Taking Temperatures At Sea View Hospital Be Improved? By Gerard Jakobi, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Perception of Power, Sex-Role Identity, and the Coping Patterns of Women by Carol Joyce, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Relationship Between Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of the Premature Infant by Violet Katz, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Relationship Between the Type of the Child's Death Whether Anticipated or Unexpected and the Jordanian Mother's Grief Responses by Inaam Abdulla Khalaf, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Anxiety, Preferred Conversational Distance and Subjective Future Life Span by Elsa Kissel, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship Between Perceptual Reactance and the Preferred Rates of Speech and Gait by Penelope M. Klatell, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - An Abstract of the Relationship of Nurse-Patient Agreement on the Importance of Outcomes to Patient Satisfaction and Length of Stay by Christine Tassone Kovner, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Separation Anxiety, Conceptual Perspective Taking, and Social Competency in Nursery School Children in a Novel Situation by Arlene S. Kreinik [envelope], 1980 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Self Concept, Field Dependence-Independence, and Judgment of Duration by Mary K. Harrison, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - An Investigation of Maternal Stress in Primigravidas as a Factor in the Production of Neonatal Pathology by Florence S. Downs, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Relation Between A Change in Social Routine and Fluctuations in Blood Pressure and Temperature by Marjorie G. Baker, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - An Investigation of Maternal Stress in Primigravidas as a Factor in the Production of Neonatal Pathology by Florence S. Downs [paperback], 1964 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Relationship of Mystical Experience, Differentiation, and Creativity in College Students by W. Richard Cowling III, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Speech Rate, Preferred Listening Rate of Speech and Perception of Time by Marie Boguslawski, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mnemonic Strategies and Parent Recall of Principles of Early Childhood Development by Anne DuVal Frost, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - The Relationship Between Appraisal of Adjustment Required by Reported Daily Life Events, Physical Symptoms and Temperature Range by Catherine A. Cassidy, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Menopausal Stage, Current Life Change, Attitude Toward Women's Roles, and Perceived Health Status in Middle-Aged Women by Nancy Sharts Engel, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - An Abstract of Pica, Hemaglobin, and Prematurity and Perinatal Mortality by Beverly Norine Dunston, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - A Study to Formulate Principles of Nursing Pertaining to Rehabilitation Which Underlie Professional Nursing Practice by Edith A. Schmitt, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between An Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between An Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton [envelope], 1968 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The Relationship of Time Experience, Creativity Traits, Differentiation and Human Field Motion by Helen M. Ference, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - An Investigation of Patient Mood as a Function of the Social Climate on Nursing Units and Patient Locus of Control by Marianne Flood, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Development of an Instrument For Assessing Perceptions of Self-Image and the Relation of Field Dependence/Independence, Amount of Weight Loss, Sex, and Perceptions of Self-Image in Individuals Who Have Lost Weight by Virginia Elaine Gallaspy, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Relationship-differentiation of Self, Complementary Psychological Need Patterns, and Marital Conflict, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - The Effects of the Individual, the Interaction and the Measurement Partner on the Measurement of Conversational Distances in Young Adult Women by Effie Sherman Hanchett [quantity: 2], 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Self Concept, Field Dependence-Independence, and Judgment of Duration by Mary K. Harrison, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - A Study of the Relationship of Total Nursing Hours to the Fatality Rate in a Specific Premature Unit by Helena Antosh and Eileen Hasselmeyer, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - An Investigation of the Effects of Therapeutic Touch on Anxiety of Hospitalized Patients by Patricia Heidt, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Level of Activation, Body Temperature and Interpersonal Conflict in Family Relationships by Carol Noll Hoskins, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Level of Activation, Temperature and Interpersonal Conflict in Family Relationships by Carol Hoskins, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Dependence and Anxiety in Male Patients Following Surgery by June Simmonds Rothberg, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Physical-Physiological Activity and Infants' Growth and Development by Luz S. Porter, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Food Iron Intake and Hemoglobin Levels in Gravidae by Lillian Runnerstrom, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - The Relationship Between Active Sleep and Developmental Abilities in Infants Residing in Foundling Institutions by Jessie Mae Pepper, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Relationship Between Patterns of Acknowledgment in Parent-Child Communication and the Child's Exploratory Behavior and Self-Differentiation by Ruth A. O'Brien, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Relationship Between Knowledge and Perception of Registered Nurses and Their Potential For Meeting the Needs of Alcoholics as Perceived by Tubercular Alcoholic Veterans by Pearle G. Morrison, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mothers' General Fearfulness, Their Daughters' Locus of Control and General Fearfulness in the Daughter by Sally Miller [envelope] [quantity: 2], 1974 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Relationship of the Duration of the Sleep State, Level of Wakefulness and Frequency of Beyond Waking Experience by Fay A. Miller [envelope], 1984 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship of Sleep, Wake, and Beyond Waking Experiences: Rogers' Concept of Sleep/Wake by Fay A. Miller [envelope], 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Civil Liability and Nursing by Beulah Eglantine Miller, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Relationship Between Maternal and Musical Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of Premature Infants by Gail B. Malloy, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Relationship Between Temperature Rhythm, Activation Rhythm and Mood Rhythm in Women by Mahassen Mansour [envelope], 1983 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Relationship Between Body Temperature Rhythm, Level of Activation Rhythm and Mood Rhythm in Women by Mahassen M. Mansour, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The Relationship Between Maternal and Musical Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of Premature Infants by Gail B. Malloy, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Hyperactivity in Children and Perception of Short Wavelength Light by Violet Malinski [envelope], 1980 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Nurses Empathy for Patients' Experience of Post-Operative Pain as a Function of the Degree of Humanism in the Nursing Environment, the Patient's Age, and Length of Time Since Surgery by Margarete Lieb Zalon, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Depression and Interpersonal Conflict in the Postpartum by Edith H. Anderson, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - A Study to Formulate Principles of Nursing Pertaining to the Maintenance and Promotion of Health Which Underlie Professional Nursing Practice by Ruth Elizabeth Anderson, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - The Relationship of Anxiety Changes and an Information-Giving Experience by Charlotte Marie Keller, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Change in Attitudes of Basic Nursing Students by Beatrice Ruth Brooks, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of Total Nursing Needs in Two General Hospitals and One Cancer Hospital as a Basis for Determining the Kind and Amount of Nursing Personnel Necessary to Meet These Needs by Rosemary Elizabeth Bouchard, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - An Investigation of Needs of Released Mental Patients on Tranquilizing Drugs in Relation to Recommending A Public Health Nursing Follow-Up Program by Ida Gelber, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between an Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Social Class and Interpersonal Interaction in Young Children by Phyllis Adeline Putnam, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 9)